[Music]
my name is Sarah Armour and I study the
science of natural and environmental
systems at Cornell University winter is
kind of harsh you have lots and lots of
snow everything's super cold any water
that's available is gonna be completely
frozen and food and shelter is really
hard to find migration is an animal
behavior that many of us are very
familiar with where all of the animals
in a population moved to a warmer
climate to avoid the worst of winter
hibernation is where animals become
dormant or inactive during the coldest
months where the hibernating animals use
way less energy and can stay cozy hidden
and safe throughout the winter so why
would some animals want to sleep through
the winter if you're an animal that eats
insects winter weather makes it really
hard to find food because insects
definitely are not active in cold
weather and if you are an animal that
eats plants winter is a difficult time
to get food because most plants are
covered in snow mammals grow thick fur
coats in preparation for winter and this
helps them conserve heat during the
coldest months many cold climate mammals
have blubber like polar bears and seals
as well as some birds like penguins the
blubber storage also is a way for
animals to have a supply of energy to
use during the winter when food is more
scarce one very good way of keeping warm
is to minimize the amount of heat that
is lost by minimizing body surface area
cold climate animals do this by having
compact and rather squat body forms with
small stout limbs ears and Tails the
snowshoe hare faces the challenge of
sinking into the deep snow as it hops
along to combat this challenge the hare
has very wide hind feet that act as
snowshoes to
distribute wait so that they remain
above the snow polar bears
Lynx mountain lions and bobcats also
have very wide feet some animals change
color in the winter to help them blend
in with their surroundings this
camouflage helps prey hide from their
predators and it helps predators keep
out of sight from their prey think of
some examples of animals you might see
as winter approaches and throughout the
coldest months you might see some fluffy
birds and puffed up squirrels with thick
coats to keep them warm maybe if you're
really observant you can see the tracks
of animals that are active through the
winter even in your own backyard it's
easy to see how animals have adapted to
winter all you have to do to see these
cool winter adaptations is look around
[Music]
you